San Diego, CA

410.980.9672 (cell) bheussler@gmail.com

Summary

I am a software engineer that been building Java applications professionally for five years. For over two years, I have worked at LifeJourney, a Baltimore-based education technology startup, building a web application used by hundreds of students on a daily basis. Java is my most proficient language, though I also work with Javascript on the front end using Angular and have used NodeJS for a few side projects.

Relevant Experience

LifeJourney.us

LifeJourney

Software Engineer

- 2014-Present - Built and maintained web application in Java using Spring and Hibernate, capable of handling
- thousands of concurrent users by means of NGINX load balancing and multiple Tomcat servers
- Developed and maintained frontend in Javascript (Angular)
- Provided backend services to iOS application via RESTful web services
- Maintained 80% unit test coverage using JUnit and Jasmine on the back and front ends respectively, as well built integration tests using Geb and REST Assured
- Wrote migration scripts in Groovy that managed the migration of multiple versions of the application to satisfy multiple clients concurrently
- Built deployment scripts in Ruby using Capistrano to manage the deployment of the application to multiple environments

MatOnto Materials Science Framework

iNovex Information Systems

Software Developer

2014

- Developed REST controllers using Groovy on Grails that orchestrated CKAN data publishing
- Built ontologies serialized in RDF to enable federated SPARQL queries across multiple data sources
- Managed and counseled interns who built customer facing website using Twitter Bootstrap

Semantic Web Integration Prototype

iNovex Information Systems

Software Developer

2012 - 2013

- Designed graph data system backed by Accumulo big data store to handle high volume integrated data, which led to increased data retrieval and application response time
- Integrated structured, semi-structured, and unstructured data using W3C Semantic Web standards, which yielded inherent data layer linkages between like or similar entities from disparate data sets

Education

Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

Aug. 2008 - May. 2012

- Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Computer Organization, Topics in Software Development

University of Nottingham

Nottingham, UK

Study Abroad

Sept. 2010 - Jan. 2011

- Relevant Courses: Operations Research and Optimization, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Graphical User Interfaces, Software Engineering Methodologies, Introduction to Formal Reasoning

Skills

Languages: Java (Proficient), Javascript (Proficient), Groovy (Proficient), Ruby (Competent), HTML/CSS (Proficient), Sass (Proficient), MySQL (Competent)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer